Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Unidentified Photographers, circa 1850-circa 1951; Series II; 359
  - Identified Locations
    - Washington
      - Tacoma
        - View of storefronts along railroad tracks in Chinatown in Tacoma, Washington, 1885; 15.3 x 20.2 cm, unmounted (Box 20)
          Before it was destroyed by a fire on November 5, 1885
        - Native American fishermen, tents, and canoes on the beach in Tacoma, Washington, 1885; 15.3 x 20.4 cm, unmounted (Box 20)
      - Wind Mountain
        - Copy photograph of a painting of Wind Mountain, Washington, Columbia River, Oregon, circa 1866; 9.1 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 20)
    - Wyoming
      - Fort Bridger
        - Copy photograph of seven views of landscape in and around Fort Bridger, Wyoming, posited surrounding a studio portrait of John "Uncle Jack" Robinson (1805-1882), circa 1867; 5.5 x 8.9 cm on mount 6.1 x 10.1 cm (Box 20)
      - Fort Laramie
        - Settlement, probably a military installation along a river, possibly Fort Laramie, Wyoming, circa 1880; 14.2 x 19.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 23.2 cm (Box 20)
      - Fort Washakie
        - View of a Shoshone Indian man, Washakie (circa 1804-1900), Chief of the Shoshone Indians, posed sitting on a horse near Fort Washakie, Wyoming, circa 1880-1890; 12.3 x 9.8 cm on mount 13.2 x 10.7 cm (Box 20)
          Circular exposure from an original Kodak camera
      - Yellowstone National Park
        - Man, woman and two girls seated near two waterfalls, possibly the Grand Canyon of Yellowstone showing the Lower Falls, circa 1890-1900; 15.5 x 20.4 cm on mount 21.6 x 27.1 cm (Box 20)
        - View of engineers beside locomotive Number 235 of the Northern Pacific Railroad, probably at a depot on the Northern Pacific Railroad Yellowstone Park Line, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming, circa 1895; 17.4 x 23.8 cm on mount 20.1 x 26.3 cm (Box 20)
      - Unidentified locations in Wyoming
        - Man dipping a bag into a hole in the ground, probably a mud pot in Wyoming, circa 1910; 11.2 x 6.7 cm, unmounted (Box 20)
          Gift of Carmen D. Valentino, 2008
    - Canada
      - Alberta
        - Lake Louise, Alberta, 1921; 7.1 x 12.9 cm, unmounted (Box 21)
      - British Columbia
        - Red Rock Bluff
          - Red Rock Bluff, Banff-Windermere Highway, British Columbia, circa 1926; 24.3 x 19.1 cm, unmounted (Box 21)
        - Shuswap Lake
          - Workers building the Canadian Pacific Railroad near Shuswap Lake, British Columbia, circa 1885; 15.9 x 20.6 cm on mount 16.4 x 21.4 cm (Box 21)
        - Stephen
          - Rocky Mountains and a locomotive of the Canadian Pacific Railway, vicinity of Stephen, British Columbia, 1890 Nov; 12.4 x 9.4 cm on mount 13.4 x 10.9 cm (Box 21)
        - Vermilion River
          - Road construction along the Vermilion River near Kootenay National Park, Banff-Windermere Highway, British Columbia, 1922; 24.3 x 19.1 cm, unmounted (Box 21)
        - Victoria
          - Blacksmith shop of John McLean near the foot of Yates Street, Victoria, British Columbia, 1880; 11.2 x 19.4 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 21)
      - Ontario
        - Lake Superior
          - "Agate Works" buildings next to a pier extending into an unidentified sound or bay, probably on Lake Superior, Ontario, circa 1890-1900; 10.5 x 18.2 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 21)
        - Thunder Cape
          - View of Thunder Cape, Thunder Bay, Lake Superior, showing the Sleeping Giant formation of mesas on Sibley Peninsula, Ontario, circa 1900; 10.9 x 18.5 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.7 cm (Box 21)
      - Saskatchewan
        - Storefronts, including a general store and the office of the Alsask News newspaper, Alsask, Saskatchewan, circa 1910; 12.9 x 17.8 cm on mount 17.9 x 23.0 cm (Box 21)
      - Yukon
        - Copy photograph of a drawing by E. B. Brown depicting the Placer Gold Claim, No. 7, Bonanza Creek, Yukon, 1898; 11.1 x 17.2 cm on mount 17.6 x 22.8 cm (Box 21)
    - Mexico
      - Chihuahua
        - View of the Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe del Paso in Ciudad Juárez, circa 1900; 10.0 x 14.1 cm on mount 10.9 x 16.6 cm (Box 21)
    - Russia
      - Siberia
        - View of the coastline on upper side of Plover Bay, circa 1895-1900; 8.8 x 11.4 cm, unmounted (Box 21)
    - Unidentified locations
      - View of locomotive number 325, Chicago, Burlington and Quincy Railroad, circa 1875; 12.1 x 20.4 cm on mount 12.2 x 20.4 cm (Box 21)
      - Overview of a collapsed mine shaft, circa 1880-1890; 11.7 x 20.1 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.6 cm (Box 21)
      - Northern Pacific Railroad locomotive number 731, circa 1885-1895; 15.1 x 20.5 cm on mount 22.8 x 27.7 cm (Box 21)
      - Shallow river running through a narrow canyon, circa 1900; 11.7 x 9.7 cm, unmounted (Box 21)
      - Wooden fence with notice, "No firs alowed les than 100 yards," as well as a partially obscured oil derrick, circa 1900; 9 x 9.1 cm on mount 12.7 x 12.7 cm (Box 21)
      - Locomotive number 2117 and crew for the Minneapolis, Saint Paul & Sault Sainte Marie Railway Company (Soo Line), circa 1910; 12.1 x 17.2 cm on mount 20.1 x 25.3 cm (Box 21)
  - Portraits
    This subseries is organized into two components, portraits of people in the landscape and studio portraits.
    - People in the landscape
      This component is arranged with images depicting American Indians and then images of other persons
      - American Indians
        - Exterior group portrait of fifteen American Indian men posed standing, probably Umatilla Indians, circa 1870; 5.5 x 8.7 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.1 cm (Box 22)
        - American Indian group of men, women, and children near a tipi, circa 1890-1900; 7.7 x 9.9 cm on mount 8.9 x 11.4 cm (Box 22)
          Image number 236
        - American Indian camp, showing summer arbor and meat drying under the arbor, circa 1890-1900; 2 photographic prints, 7.9 x 10.1 cm on mount 8.8 x 11.5 cm (Box 22)
        - Two Omaha Indian men with tipis in background, circa 1890-1900; 9.3 x 16.5 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
        - Exterior portrait of Sioux Indians, consisting of an elderly man and woman with a child sitting on the ground in front of a tent, circa 1890-1900; 9.8 x 14.1 cm on mount 10.7 x 16.5 cm (Box 22)
          Image number 267
        - Blackfoot Indian lodge tipi, 1896; 9.8 x 12.9 cm on mount 10.8 x 13.3 cm (Box 22)
          Image number 472
        - Exterior portrait of eight Apache Indians, consisting of three children, two women, and three men, posed next to a brick building, circa 1900; 11.0 x 18.2 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
        - Two Havasupai Indian boys seated with baskets, 1907; 8.2 x 6.9 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
        - Havasupai Indian woman carrying a basket, 1907; 8.2 x 6.9 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
        - Havasupai Indian boy in front of house, 1907; 8.2 x 6.9 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
      - Other persons in landscapes
        - Informal portrait of men drinking coffee at a folding table, circa 1867; 5.4 x 9.5 cm on mount 6.1 x 10.1 cm (Box 22)
        - Copy photograph of a drawing of James Bridger (1804-1881) a mountain man, trapper, scout and guide, circa 1870; 9.3 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 22)
        - Copy photograph of troops in the field with horse and rifles, possibly members of the 6th Cavalry of the United States Army, circa 1875; 11.3 x 18.1 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 22)
        - Copy photograph of a drawing by W. E. B. Trowbridge, Jr., entitled "Grangers versus Grasshoppers, or the Irrepressible Conflict," which depicts large grasshoppers gathering wheat and attacking a farmer while his family looks on., circa 1875; 5.8 x 8.9 cm on mount 6.3 x 10.6 cm (Box 22)
        - Overview of canvas tents, men, and horses in camp, possibly a prospecting camp, circa 1880-1890; 11.7 x 20.0 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 22)
        - Five loggers with a team of two oxen felling a large tree, circa 1885-1890; 19.7 x 11.4 cm on mount 21.3 x 13.1 cm (Box 22)
        - A group of twenty-two men clearing trees from land beside a waterway, circa 1885-1895; 11.3 x 19.0 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.6 cm (Box 22)
        - Cargo sled train, with men and horses, circa 1890-1900; 12.7 x 18.5 cm on mount 22.7 x 28.2 cm (Box 22)
        - Steam locomotive with two men posed standing beside it, circa 1895; 11.4 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.1 x 21.1 cm (Box 22)
        - Crowd gathered at the Fremont Monument, 1896; 10.7 x 13.3 cm on mount 12.4 x 15.3 cm (Box 22)
        - Group portrait of five African American women and four African American men in front of a house, circa 1900; 12.4 x 17.6 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.4 cm (Box 22)
        - Children, two children in a donkey-drawn cart, and a child sitting on the donkey supported by an elderly man, circa 1900; 8.5 x 8.3 cm on mount 12.8 x 12.8 cm (Box 22)
        - Exposition display for Alaska, which includes basket weavers from the Aleutian islands, sled dogs, a gold miner, and a totem pole, circa 1900; 12.8 x 17.9 cm on mount 13.4 x 18.8 cm (Box 22)
        - Baptizing by Christian Church at the home of J. V. Jolly, which depicts a large group of children, women, and men along a river witnessing the baptism of three women by Jolly, 1901; 16.2 x 21.7 cm on mount 20.8 x 25.4 cm (Box 22)
        - Exterior portrait of Gus Dietzil and Max Dietzil (possibly a misspelling of Dietzel) holding a small folding bellows camera, probably a Folding Pocket Kodak No. 1-A, circa 1910; 8.0 x 13.6 cm on mount 12.8 x 18.5 cm (Box 22)
        - Interior of a country store with six and two women, circa 1920; 12.7 x 17.8 cm on mount 19.9 x 25.0 cm (Box 22)
          Manuscript on verso identifies three of the men as Fred Braken, Billy Aetrilis, and Fred Worren
        - Stream with a waterfowl in it, circa 1930; 11.7 x 7.0 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
        - Copy photograph of an exterior portrait of a man mounted on a horse among automobiles, identified as John M. Walker riding the mare "Chippy," circa 1930, circa 1970; 25.3 x 20.3 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
          Photograph print reproduced from the California State Library, Sacramento, California
          Manuscript inscription on verso identifies Walker as a direct descendant of Joel Pickens Walker (born 1797), a delegate to the first California Constitutional Convention in Monterey in 1849
        - Copy photograph of an informal portrait of Warburton Pike (1861-1915) posed standing and smoking a pipe, 1914, circa 1970; 19.7 x 12.6 cm, unmounted (Box 22)
          Photograph print reproduced from the British Columbia Archives, Victoria, British Columbia, Canada
          Pike was a British explorer, entrepreneur, naturalist, and author, primarily in northwestern Canada
    - Studio portraits
      This component is organized by the surname of individual subjects, followed by unidentified individuals, then by groups of individuals organized by the surname of the first identified individual on the far left of the frame followed by groups of unidentified individuals.
      - Studio portrait of Mr. Averell, circa 1870; 8.9 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Johnny Baker (1869-1931), circa 1890; 14.5 x 9.5 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        Baker was a sharpshooter, entertainer, and close friend of William F. "Buffalo Bill" Cody. He founded of the Buffalo Bill Memorial Museum in Golden, Colorado
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of William Henry Bisbee (1840-1942), circa 1876; 13.0 x 10.5, unmounted (Box 23)
        Bisbee served in the American Civil War, Indian Wars, and Spanish American War, as well as serving as a military governor in the Philippines.
      - Studio portrait of Augustine Magloire Alexander Blanchet (1797-1887), Bishop of Walla Walla, Washington, circa 1864-1866; 8.8 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.3 cm (Box 23)
        Two-cent revenue stamp affixed to the verso of the mount
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Georges Ernest Jean-Marie Boulanger (1837-1891), a French general and reactionary politician., circa 1890; 15.1 x 9.5 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Captain H. J. Burns of the California National Guard and the California Rifle Team with a rifle, circa 1877; 14.5 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Daniel Adams Butterfield (1831-1901), circa 1865; 8.4 x 5.3 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
        Butterfield was a New York businessman, a Union general in the American Civil War, and Assistant United States Treasurer in New York
      - Studio portrait of Albert A. Cohen, a member of the Knickerbocker Revolver Club, a part of the Knickerbocker Athletic Club in New York, New York, 1896; 14.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.3 x 10.6 cm (Box 23)
      - Printed studio portrait of James S. Conlin (circa 1832-1902) surrounded by drawing of guns, circa 1890; 11.5 x 7.3 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
        Conlin was an expert marksman. He also owned and operated a shooting gallery on Broadway Avenue and 31st Street in New York, New York
      - Studio portrait of Selucius Garfielde (1822-1881), 1865; 9.2 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        Garfielde was a delegate to the United States House of Representatives from Washington Territory from 1869 to 1873
      - Studio portrait of John Smith Griffin (1807-1899), circa 1870; 10.5 x 6.5 cm, unmounted tintype (Box 23)
        Griffin was an American missionary in Oregon Country that participated at the Champoeg Meetings that created the Provisional Government of Oregon in 1843
      - Studio portrait of Hill Harmon (born 1823), circa 1867; 8.9 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
        Harmon arrived at Puget Sound in the former Washington Territory in 1850 and engaged in various enterprises, including the head of an insane asylum, operating a logging camp, serving as territorial treasurer, and building the Harmon Hotel at Steilacoom, Washington
      - Studio portrait of James Henry Dickey Henderson (1810-1885), created in Eugene, Oregon, 1866 June; 8.8 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        Henderson was a Member of the United States House of Representatives from Oregon's At-large district, 1865-1867
        An organge 1862 bank check certificate revenue stamp depicting George Washington for two cents is affixed to the verso and hand-cancelled in ink by "NEB, June/66"
      - Studio portrait of Hole in the Day, also known as Bugonaygeeshig (1827-1868), a Chippewa Indian chief, circa 1867; 9.2 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of George Alonzo Johnson (1824-1903), circa 1870, circa 1900; 12.7 x 8.8 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
        Johnson operated steamboats on the Colorado River from 1852-1877
        Manuscript accompanying the photograph provides a brief biographical sketch of Johnson
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Maria Estéfana Alvarado Johnson (born 1840) wearing a hat, circa 1870, circa 1900; 12.7 x 8.9 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
        In 1859, she married George Alonzo Johnson (born 1824)
        Manuscript inscription on an envelope accompanying the photograph states Johnson was "wife of Geo. Alonzo Johnson and niece of Don Pio Rico"
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Maria Estéfana Alvarado Johnson (born 1840), circa 1870, circa 1900; 12.7 x 8.9 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of a Kiowa Indian man, identified as Kau-Tau-Bone (1847-1927), also known as Gotebo, circa 1885; 13.8 x 9.8 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
        Misidentified on verso as Sitting Bull
      - Studio portrait of a Cheyenne Indian man, identified as Sampson Kelley, circa 1885; 13 x 9.6 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Heber Chase Kimball (1801-1868), circa 1867; 9.2 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
        Manuscript inscription on the verso identifies Kimball as "Herber C. Kimble"
        Kimball was a leader in the early Latter-day Saint movement. He served as one of the original twelve apostles in the early Mormon church, and as first counselor to Brigham Young in the First Presidency of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints
      - Studio portrait of a man, probably Mr. Laughton, wearing a Masonic order lapel pin, circa 1910; 17.7 x 12.5 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Clarence Long (born circa 1883), a juvenile rifle sharpshooter, 1894; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Mr. W. H. Magill, 1868 Apr; 9.4 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        Manuscript inscription on the verso: "W. H. Magill, 16 Apl 68"
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Charles H. Mason (1830-1859), image originally made in 1853, circa 1867; 9.5 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        Mason was appointed first Secretary of the Washington Territory in 1854
      - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Medicine Bull (Tatanka Wakan), Lower Brule Lakota, circa 1867; 14.3 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.6 cm (Box 23)
        Probably copied from an original studio portrait created by Charles Lewis Hamilton (born circa 1837), a photographer in Sioux City, Iowa, and Fort Randall, South Dakota
        Medicine Bull was a leading chief on the Lower Brule Reservation, opposite Fort Thompson, South Dakota, and a signatory of the Sioux Treaty of 1868
      - Studio portrait of Simpson P. Moses (born 1823), circa 1860; 9.6 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 5.8 cm (Box 23)
        Manuscript inscription on verso: "arrived in territory [in] 1851."
        Moses was the customs collector at Olympia, Washington, 1851-1853
      - Studio portrait of an Apache Chiricahua man, identified as Chief Natchez (also known as Nei-Chi-Ri or Naiche), circa 1890; 12.9 x 9.7 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Old Man Afraid of His Horses (1802-1887), also known as Man of Whose Horses They are Afraid, an elderly Teton Indian man, circa 1886; 14.1 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        Old Man Afraid of His Horses was a signatory on the Treaty of Fort Laramie (also called the Sioux Treaty of 1868) was an agreement between the United States and the Lakota nation, Yanktonai Sioux, Santee Sioux, and Arapaho signed in 1868 at Fort Laramie in the Wyoming Territory
      - Studio portrait of Ethelbert Patterson Oliphant (1803-1884), circa 1870; 9.5 x 5.8 cm on mount 9.9 x 6.0 cm (Box 23)
        Oliphant served as a adjutant in the Black Hawk War in 1832, with then private, Abraham Lincoln. Lincoln later appointed him an Associate Judge of the Supreme Court of the Washington Territory
      - Studio portrait of a Creek Indian two men posed sitting and a Creek Indian boy posed standing, identified as Legus Choteau Perryman (born 1838), head chief of the Creek Indian Nation from 1887 to 1895, and his sons, circa 1900; 13.4 x 9.6 cm on mount 14.9 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of John Wesley Powell (1834-1902), 1875; 15.5 x 10.5 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of members a tour of the west by John Aaron Rawlins (1831-1869), 1867; 16.6 x 23.8 cm on mount 19.3 x 26.0 cm (Box 23)
        Individuals identified from left to right. Back row: James M. Wheelan, John K. Mizner (misidentified by an inscription on the mount as Henry E. Noyes), Dr. Henry C. Terry, and John E. Corwith. Front row: David Van Lennep, John R. Duff, Grenville Mellen Dodge (1831-1916), John Aaron Rawlins, William Mck. Dunn
        Rawlins was a United States Army general during the American Civil War, a confidant of Ulysses S. Grant, and a United States Secretary of War
      - Copy photograph of a painting of Louis David Riel (1844-1885) owned by Abraham Guay, circa 1886; 12.3 x 9.4 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        Printed below the photograph on the mount are declarations in French by Riel familythat this image is a copy of a portrait owned by Abraham Guay
        Originally laid-in a copy of NapoleÌon Thompson, The Gibbet of Regina, The Truth About Riel, Sir John A. Macdonald and His Cabinet Before Public Opinion, by One Who Knows (New York: Thompson & Moreau, 1886)
      - Studio portrait of John "Uncle Jack" Robinson (1805-1882), trapper, trader, and a friend of James Bridger (1804-1881), circa 1867; 8.7 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.0 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Saucy Chief, also known as Ga-hi-ge-wa-da-in-ga or Playful Chief (born circa 1827), circa 1870-1872; 20.1 x 14.1 cm on mount 25.2 x 20.4 cm (Box 23)
        Possibly created for William Henry Blackmore (1827-1878)
      - Studio portrait of Lillian Frances Smith (1871-1930) also known as "The California Girl," Champion Rifle Shot of the World and "Princess Wenona", circa 1890; 13.3 x 19.0 cm on mount 13.8 x 19.5 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Samuel Davis Sturgis (1822-1889), circa 1885; 23.0 x 16.5 cm on mount 25.0 x 17.5 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of an Brulé Sioux Indian man, identified as Chief Two Strike, also known as Nomkahpa (1832-1923), circa 1895; 15.0 x 10.4 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 23)
      - Studio portrait of Charles H. Utter (1838-after 1912), also known as "Colorado Charley", circa 1880; 13.9 x 9.5 cm, unmounted (Box 23)
        Utter was a trapper, guide, and prospector in Colorado, and companion of James "Wild Bill" Butler Hickok (1837-1876)
      - Studio portrait of an elderly American Indian man, identified as White Buffalo Chief, probably a Sioux Indian, circa 1890; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 23)
        Image number 772
      - Studio portrait of a Sioux Indian man, identified as White Bull, also known as Tah-tonka-skah, a signer of the Fort Laramie Treaty of April 29, 1868, circa 1885; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 23)
        Image number 640
      - Studio portrait of a Kiowa Indian man, identified as Chief White Horse, also known as Tsen-Tainte (died 1892), circa 1885; 13.9 x 9.8 cm on mount 18.0 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        Manuscript inscription on verso identifies White Horse as "the noted raider into Texas"
      - Studio portrait of a Teton Sioux Indian man, identified as Woman's Dress, circa 1885; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 23)
        Manuscript inscription on verso identifies Woman's Dress as "Chief at Pine Ridge Agency, South Dakota. He saved General Crook's life," which refers to George Crook (1828-1890)
        Image number 459
      - Unidentified individuals
        - Studio portrait of an unidentified general in the United States Army, posed sitting and holding a hat and sword, circa 1850; 18.4 x 13.4 cm on mount 12.2 x 18.6 cm (Box 23)
          Salted paper print
        - Studio portrait of a Kickapoo Indian man, identified as Teapos, possibly a delegate to Mexico City, circa 1864; 9.6 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.3 cm (Box 23)
          Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2012
        - Studio portrait of a Nez Perce Indian man posed sitting and holding a peace pipe, identified as a member of the Walwama tribe in the Willowa Valley, circa 1867; 9.2 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1870; 8.5 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1870; 8.5 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of an elderly man, circa 1870; 9.7 x 6.5 cm, unmounted tintype (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of an American Indian girl posed sitting and a girl posed standing, probably Umatilla Indians, circa 1870; 9.2 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of a young American Indian man posed sitting and a boy posed standing, probably Umatilla Indians, circa 1870; 9.5 x 5.6 cm on mount 9.9 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)
        - Studio portrait of an Umatilla Indian man, identified as a chief, circa 1870; 9.2 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 23)